Commanders family. We have a very, very
special guest here on Command Center for
the first time on Command Center. Y'all
seen him on ESPN. Y'all seen him
everywhere football related. Dan
Orlovski, welcome him into the building,
sir. How you doing?
>> I'm doing great. It's good to be with
you, man. Good to talk some Commanders
football with you.
>> Oh man, I cannot wait to talk all about
it. And I was like looking it up. I was
like, let me look on Twitter and see Dan
Rolovski/Commanders
and see the kind of things he was
saying. And you would do nothing but
show love. So, we appreciate you, you
know. So, I don't got to hit you with
nothing crazy. I just want to talk about
>> nothing too heavy. Nothing too heavy.
Nothing too heavy.
>> Nothing too heavy at all. But Dan, I
mean, it shows that your poll, your
finger is always on the polls. And it
seems like the Commanders have been
something worth talking about a lot,
especially in NFL free agency. How do
you feel the Commanders fared? How do
you feel AP fared in this year's free
agency?
>> Yeah. Yeah. I'm bullish on on Washington
right now. And it it's interesting
because full transparency coming off of
Jaden's rookie year and kind of that
magical year of 24, I was a little bit
more hesitant on 25 just because 24 was
so magical and these comebacks and you
had these fourth down conversions and it
kind of at least I thought like
overshadow a little bit of like where
this rebuild was and you know some
unfortunate stuff, injuries, all that
stuff happens in 24 and then you go
into, excuse me, into 25 and now you're
into 26 in the start of the 26
offseason. It's Washington's quietly had
this this unnoticed or untalked about
but really strong season. You know, like
you looked at this football team and you
said, "Okay, first of all, you have this
new offensive coordinator hire and David
Blau that's probably a little bit of
this unknown, but he comes from some
really good football background both as
a player and then coaches that he's been
and system that he's been around in the
NFL." And then you look at some of the
defensive pieces, obviously a new
defensive coordinator as well, but some
of the defensive pieces you add, you had
two edge rushers, edge rushers, Taan had
such an outstanding year in New England.
always still just scratching the surface
if you talk to defensive people and the
way that they can get after the passer.
I've been a Leo Chanel guy since calling
his games at Wisconsin. Just a just a
big time football player at linebacker.
Nick Cross from Indy's a really good
addition. Just a smart smart safety. Um
I'm a CHIG guy as well at tight end. I
just think if you just put him with a
good quarterback, you'll see the numbers
and production go up. Um, and so like
you're watching this organization just,
you know, get younger, get more
athletic, get more versatile pieces. And
so, uh, I I think it's been a, for some
reason, quiet, um, from the national
perspective, but very strong offseason.
>> I'm I'm very shocked to hear you say it
is so quiet, I guess, for us because
we're in house, right? It's been very
very loud. There's been a lot of
celebration on what Adam Peters was able
to accomplish, but you said it's been a
little quiet, maybe even a little
underrated. Is it fair to say that maybe
you think the Commanders may have won
free agency when it's all said and done?
>> Yeah, I think you when you look at
teams, it's always like we we the free
agency world in the NFL is almost
extremes. It it's the who spent the most
money and then we automatically and
there's been some recent um evidence to
say that that that is going to equate to
wins. So you like who spent the most
money? They've had the best offseason or
they won free agency or you know this
team that maybe they didn't spend
anything because they're in that they
don't have it. Um they're in a win now
mode. They've already paid all those
those players. And I I I think it's just
you know the win free agency. Yes.
Because there wasn't necessarily the
massive contract that doled out that
maybe everyone scratched their head at.
And I don't want to minimize OA got paid
a lot of money, but again, a lot of
people sit there and say Ooway's just
scratching the surface. I think he fits
kind of the the the scheme that they're
going to evolve to, at least
expectationwise in Washington. So, um,
yeah, I think that there was this almost
like second iteration in this Jaden
Daniels era in a way, you know, and it's
so like yeah, the free agency you just
check off is like a lot of really good
pieces, a lot of really smart pieces
added, a lot of winners too, a lot of
guys that won like been was were around
places that won football games and it
seemed like there was an emphasis on
that, right? like bringing guys and
especially on the defensive side of the
ball. You have a guy in Leo that you
mentioned, two Super Bowls, three Super
Bowl appearances. We have a bunch of
different guys, Odaf who was able to
break records in the playoffs as far as
sacks are concerned. So, we got guys
with that playoff potential. And I want
to talk about this defense because we
all know that the Commanders really
struggled on defense last year, but now
we have a new defensive coordinator and
Donte Jones. Now, we add all of these
different pieces. cuz I got to imagine
you and the people that you talk to on a
regular basis see the commanders defense
taking a big move up this year.
>> Oh, huge. Huge. And it's going to be for
me. I think the most interesting part is
like who are they going to be
identitywise? Because I would tell you
Dan Quinn's past, brilliant coach, but
his past and Dante at least the
experience that I would imagine he
gathered in Minnesota, it's a little
different. You know, Dan is a little bit
more of like I'm going to line up and
play one certain coverage and we're
going to come after you and there's
going to be this chess piece that we
move around a little bit like Micah
Parsons and I know it's his Seattle
background maybe is a little bit more
covered three and then Donte you know if
you know anything about bean Flores the
defense according to Minnesota it's I
call it Star Wars you know it's this
this all these moving pieces and all
these different pressures and coverages
and it's uh in a a little bit like maybe
unstructured chaos. Um, but they get to
their places and so it's going to be
very interesting to watch the the the
brain trust and the scheme and kind of
what do they hang their hat on because I
kind of live in a world if you look at
the defenses right now in the NFL, it's
you don't necessarily want to be
predictable in what you do. You also
don't want to be overly creative in what
you do because then there's there's no
cornerstone to your defense. So I think
scheme wise. So I think it'll be
interesting to see just defensively what
do they settle on and who they are. And
then I still think in this will lead to
the draft is okay. Well, who's really
like the the matchup piece for them? Got
two good edge rushers now. But I still
believe that those really good defensive
coaches have just that piece. Dan Quinn
being one of them. Just that piece that
they can move around to create matchups
almost like offenses do. But yeah, I I
think that this defense is just from a
youth athleticism and and um skill
standpoint is much improved.
>> So when you look at the number seven
pick, because you mentioned the draft,
do you feel that there's going to be
somebody there at number seven that is
that defensive course? I don't put you
on a spot here, but I have to ask
because it sounds as if maybe you're
seeing them maybe maybe go that route.
>> Yeah, I think the seven pick is is I
think the whole NFC East is really
interesting draftwise. Um, but I think
it's interesting because I could sit
here and unequivocally tell tell you
like, yeah, if there's a player that a
Caleb DS or a Sunny Styles falls, both
Ohio State guys, you sit there and say
you just it makes a lot of sense to have
a piece like that. I'll go to Dante. A
huge part of Minnesota's defensive
success is having a safety. And I'll put
up a Harrison Smith type of safety that
was super smart, could be a great liar
with coverages, understood everybody's
job, and everyone says that about a
Caleb DS or you say the Sunny Styles
type of player that is that change,
move, piece, crazy athlete. I can get
him in rush situations. You get Okay.
So, like I could sit there and I think
everybody if one of those two players
were the selection, you would sit there
and say that totally makes sense for
exactly who Washington wants to be. But
then I could also go, well, I could see
if a Jeremiah Love falls to them. I
don't want to say false, but is
available at seven. You know, then you
go, man, could you replicate the Jaylen
Herd Saquon Barkley running attack of
2024? or for Carnell Tate the wide
receiver from Ohio State goes and says
because David Blau I think of David Blau
and I go okay David Blau was in
Minnesota when they had a Justin
Jefferson and two wide receivers said
maybe it's an Addison or a Theelin and
then he's in Detroit when they had
Jameson Williams and I'm on Ross St.
Brown. Okay. Well, we know they have
Terry McLaren, you know. So, what
happens if a Carnell Tate is there or
Jordan Tyson's there? Like, do they want
that second wide receiver piece? That's
why I think there's a lot of available
options.
>> And I mean, that's a great position to
be in, right? And I think that the way
AP and DQ tackled free agency is why we
can sit and speculate. I think a couple
months ago, we were pretty locked in and
saying, "Okay, we're probably going to
get a defensive guy." But now, like you
say, you mention a guy like Jeremiah
Love. And I think when you hear a name
like that and you hear a team in the
commanders who were just two years ago
in the NFC Championship just just this
close, right?
>> You get a guy like Jeremiah Love and you
say, "Man, he might be able to get us to
that promised land." I look at Jaden
Daniels and Jeremiah Love in the RPO in
the Renzo and you say, "How do you guard
that?" When you look at a guy like
Jeremiah Love, do you think he is one of
those players that could take this
offense to the next level?
>> I think he takes any offense to the next
level. I think he's 1500 yards when he
steps onto the field as a rookie in the
NFL. Uh just and I've this has been a
parade of mine this off season. We we
cannot just box him into running back.
Yes, he's going to play that position,
but he is so
versatile and athletic in the things
that you can do. There are people who
are widely respected that would sit
there and tell you if you had him just
play wide receiver in the slot, he'd
catch 60 plus patches passes just as a
slot receiver in the NFL. And to context
it, everyone knows that Jir Gibbs is one
of the great backs in the in the NFL,
one of the great football players in the
NFL, let alone young. He's three in
bigger than Jir Gibbs. He's 15 lbs
heavier and he ran the same speed just
for the context. You mean he had his
average touchdown at Notre Dame was 36
yards average. So it you you're talking
about just a a uniquely gifted player.
And so um I think he changes any
offenses and certainly and that's why
I'll continue to point to like David
Blau where was he last as a player?
Detroit he was there when they took Jir.
So, it's just like you've got a guy that
has a little bit of just a vantage point
of hearing coaches talk about this type
of player and then watching how teams
defensively handled this type of player.
Yeah. And I I I just think um you know,
if you attach him to an offense that has
an improved offensive line, has this
dynamic quarterback, has some good young
pieces at tight end and wide receiver
group that, you know, includes Terry
McLaren. Yeah, I love it,
>> man. Listen, if the fans weren't already
begging their hands on the table, say,
"Get us Jeremiah Love." When you broke
that down, they might be sold. Now, my
final question for you, Dan, cuz I know
you're a very, very busy guy. We talked
about Jaden and you mentioned his second
year and all the things that went into
that, right? Like, it was injuries, it
was losing a loved one, it was going
through personal things in life and also
just going through being a sophomore in
the NFL, which I know you know is very,
very tough. But now you look at year
three. And year three is that year for
those quarterbacks where you really feel
like you know what you're getting. What
are you expecting to see from Jaden
Daniels in 2026?
>> Yeah, I would fully expect this massive
step from at least last year and kind of
the what we thought would be the runway
from year one to year two. You know,
that year one that was so magical. And
you know, it's also you go through a
training camp and your best receiver is
not there. So, it's there's just so many
butterflies, you know, attached to kind
of not having Terry there last year. And
so I think now with this new offense and
and some of these new pieces, I there's
no bigger fan of Jaden than mine than
than me. I think people know that going
back to some of my thoughts pre-draft
process. And so healthy, no question.
You want to keep him healthy. I love if
the offense is going to be kind of what
I expect it to be. Um I thought one of
Jaden's greatest strengths was throwing
some of those intermediate routes and
those big crossing progression routes.
that should be a foundational piece of
this offense. They should move him a
lot. So, the athleticism would be a part
of it. How comfortable he gets getting
under center will be a big deal. But
yeah, I still think honestly that they
need to add at least another offensive
weapon talent, whether that's Love or a
receiver, someone like that. But if they
do that, yeah, I would I would fully
expect us to see in 26 the version of
quarterback that we saw in 24. Dan
Orlovski, one of the best to ever do it.
And I had a feeling before we met from
afar that you might be a little bit of a
Commanders fan. I think we are bringing
you into the fold here as our Commanders
family. Dan, thank you so much for your
time. Thank you so much for your
analysis. And we hope to talk to you
soon, sir. Thank you.
>> Ah, it's good to be with you. Good luck.
I appreciate you guys. And there's a
there's a small part. I married a girl
from Philadelphia. Okay. So there
there's that reality for me, but there's
a small part I'm always rooting for for
certainly players like Jaden and an
organization like Washington.
>> Oh man, we love that. Dan, again, thank
you so much for your time, man. And you
enjoy yourself. We know it's about to
get pretty busy. You enjoy the draft,
bro. Hey,
>> appreciate